And because they can live up to 100 years old, giant clams make vital indicators of coral reef health. So when giant clams start to disappear from coral reefs, their absence can serve as an alarm bell for scientists to start paying attention, similar to the canary in a coal mine. But giant clams are endangered. The largest clam in the world is facing the threat of extinction, with more than 50 percent of the wild population severely depleted. And the ecological benefits of having giant clams on coral reefs are likely to continue only if populations are healthy, making their conservation paramount. So I stand here today to give a voice to the giant clams, because I care a whole lot for these amazing animals, and they deserve to be cared for. It is time for the giant clams to step out of their shells, and show the world that they, too, can be the heroes of the oceans. Thank you very much. (Applause)
Y como pueden vivir hasta los 100 años, los ostras gigantes son indicadores vitales de salud de arrecifes de coral. Por eso, cuando comienzan a desaparecer los arrecifes, su ausencia se puede interpretar como una alarma para que los científicos presten atención, son como el canario en una mina de carbón. Pero las ostras gigantes están en peligro. La mayor ostra del mundo está en vías de extinción, con una merma de más del 50 % de la población. Los beneficios ecológicos de que existan ostras gigantes en los arrecifes de coral solo persistirán si las poblaciones son sanas, haciendo su conservación primordial. Por eso, estoy aquí hoy para hablar por las ostras gigantes, porque me preocupo de verdad por estos animales extraordinarios, y porque ellos merecen nuestra atención. Es hora de que de las ostras gigantes salgan de sus conchas y muestren al mundo que, ellas también pueden ser heroínas de los océanos. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)